<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>RPG on Chaslinux&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/rpg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RPG on Chaslinux&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 12:25:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/rpg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knights of Pen &amp; Paper II</title>
      <link>/posts/knights_of_pen_and_paper_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 12:25:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/knights_of_pen_and_paper_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-dice-game-with-a-sense-of-humour&#34;&gt;A dice game with a sense of humour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If games like &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/200710/Torchlight_II/&#34;&gt;Torchlight II&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://diablo3.blizzard.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;Diablo III&lt;/a&gt;, or my favourite - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grimdawn.com/&#34;&gt;Grim Dawn&lt;/a&gt; are your thing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/310060/Knights_of_Pen_and_Paper_2/&#34;&gt;Knights of Pen &amp;amp; Paper II&lt;/a&gt; will seem like a snooze-fest to you. While Knights has elements of a role playing game, it’s not an “Action” role playing game (ARPG), but more mimics the kind of play you might get from playing Dungeons and Dragons with a game master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the game is NOT multiplayer, so one of the best parts of D&amp;amp;D is missing from Knights of Pen &amp;amp; Paper II, but if you’re okay with playing solo, this might be a fun title for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legend of Grimrock - a better Bards Tale III</title>
      <link>/posts/legend_of_grimrock_a_better_bards_tale_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 20:38:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/legend_of_grimrock_a_better_bards_tale_iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;bards-tale-iii--my-introduction-to-3d-like-adventure&#34;&gt;Bards Tale III – my introduction to 3D like adventure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 1980’s I worked for Simcoe Computer Consultants at the 400 Market, outside of Barrie, Ontario. The 400 Market was a mixed market of many vendors, one of which was Simcoe Computer Consultants. I spent the weekends manning the company’s booth, selling the odd item, and spreading the word about the company’s computers and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One weekend Cec, one of the company owners, mentioned that a lead from the market had helped them sell a bunch of computers, and I was welcome to pick a piece of software as a reward. I picked Bard’s Tale III, Thief of Fate, a dungeon crawling game with a 3D-like interface. Bard’s Tale III quickly became one of my favourite games, it mixed D&amp;amp;D elements with a more urgent element where one wrong turn could lead to a face to face encounter with deadly monsters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
