<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Chaslinux&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chaslinux&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 18:24:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Computer Recycling&#39;s PXE Network Server</title>
      <link>/posts/computer_recyclings_pxe_network_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 18:24:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/computer_recyclings_pxe_network_server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;pxe-network-installation&#34;&gt;PXE network installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Linux distribution web sites describe the process of how to download an &lt;strong&gt;ISO&lt;/strong&gt;, and create a bootable USB key. While USB keys are great if you&amp;rsquo;re working on your own computer, when you need to scale up and install across a number of systems there are more efficient ways of deploying Linux. One of those ways is to network boot, and install from a PXE (Preboot Execution Environment) server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steam On Linux Mint 21.3 (Virginia)</title>
      <link>/posts/steam_on_linux_mint_21_3_virginia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 09:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/steam_on_linux_mint_21_3_virginia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;debian-package-over-flatpak-but-get-it-from-steam&#34;&gt;Debian package over flatpak, but get it from Steam&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving from Xubuntu to Linux Mint XFCE was not as seemless as I’d hoped it would be. The last time I gave Linux Mint serious consideration was over 13 years ago when the Computer Recycling Project at The Working Centre was looking for a replacement for Ubuntu 10.04 (the next version would include the Unity desktop which wouldn’t run on a lot of our laptops at the time).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned encoding media under linux</title>
      <link>/posts/lessons_learned_encoding_media_under_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 11:26:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lessons_learned_encoding_media_under_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardware-and-linux-distribution-differences&#34;&gt;Hardware and Linux Distribution Differences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post covers a bunch of areas of media decoding and encoding that I’ve discovered over a number of years using Debian-based distributions like Xubuntu, and Linux Mint. Primarily I’ll cover some of the differences between Xubuntu and Linux Mint, how various hardware (CPUs and graphics cards) encode video, and some of the “gotchas” when it comes to different methods as they apply to Handbrake (software) and MakeMKV.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to play Jazz Jackrabbit on Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/how_to_play_jazz_jackrabbit_on_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:13:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how_to_play_jazz_jackrabbit_on_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;jazz-jackrabbit--an-introduction&#34;&gt;Jazz Jackrabbit – an introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 1994 the World Wide Web (WWW) was just starting to catch on, mostly via a dial-up connection. Bulletin Board Systems (BBS) were starting to be on the way out, but at the time I was running a bulletin board for a local computer club. One of the attractions of bulletin board systems (besides online games/aka doors, message boards, and chatting) were the extensive “shareware” software collections. If you weren’t going to a computer store to buy software, you were probably calling a bulletin board to download shareware or freeware software. Shareware software became known as “try before you buy” software. In most cases software was fully functional, but limited in some way (for example: a game where you could play the first few levels, but if you wanted more, you had to send the shareware author money for the rest of the software).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why command line skills are important - Troubleshooting...</title>
      <link>/posts/why_command_line_skills_are_important/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:41:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why_command_line_skills_are_important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I was checking out Youtube videos about a Linux-related program, and I came across a comment in one of the videos that I’ve seen before (I’m paraphrasing this to not identify the video or commenter):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;random comment on a Linux video:&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;Those commands don’t work. In Windows, you don’t have to write a book to install something. I’m going back to Windows.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comment isn&amp;rsquo;t a question, but a statement: &lt;code&gt;Linux is difficult, Windows is easier.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Artificial Intelligence on Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/simple_artificial_intelligence_on_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:44:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/simple_artificial_intelligence_on_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-look-at-artificial-intelligence&#34;&gt;Initial look at artificial intelligence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might be a bit late to the game, but I’ve started looking at what we need at the Computer Recycling Project to run artificial intelligence models locally (on the machine, versus on the server) under Linux. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ollama.com/download&#34;&gt;The Ollama project&lt;/a&gt; makes it very easy to install a number of artificial intelligence models under Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once ollama is installed you can download a model by typing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ollama pull &amp;lt;model name&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you wanted to pull Llama 3.2 you would type:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Fix] Suspend doesn&#39;t work on Linux Mint XFCE Lenovo Yoga S1</title>
      <link>/posts/suspend_doesnt_work_on_linux_mint_xfce_lenovo_yoga_s1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:38:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/suspend_doesnt_work_on_linux_mint_xfce_lenovo_yoga_s1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;suspend-doesnt-work-on-some-linux-distributions--lenovo-yoga-s1&#34;&gt;Suspend doesn’t work on some Linux distributions – Lenovo Yoga S1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our experience with Linux Mint XFCE has been pretty good so far at The Working Centre’s Computer Recycling Project, but we recently ran into an issue where a couple of Lenovo Yoga S1 laptops refused to suspend when the suspend button was clicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before someone goes on about Linux, I want to point out a couple of things:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our TrueNAS Server</title>
      <link>/posts/our_truenas_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:56:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/our_truenas_server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-lives-it-dies&#34;&gt;It lives, it dies!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our new TrueNAS server is up, and all the hardware is working, but not without some hiccups on the way. After taking a lot longer to build than expect, I was so happy the other evening when I posted about the successful Power On Self Test (POST), and the new RAM (32GB) being properly detected. Exhausted at the end of the day I left the drives disconnected and the video card out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the NAS - hardware hiccups</title>
      <link>/posts/building_the_nas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 08:17:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/building_the_nas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;most-of-the-hardware-is-assembled&#34;&gt;Most of the hardware is assembled&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks have been extremely busy, so I knew last night would probably be the only time I would get this week to work on the NAS. I’m glad I started building the NAS last night as it took much longer than anticipated. I finally finished the build at 10pm last night (and it’s still not quite complete).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Intel Core i3 7100 CPU close-up&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;/img/intel_core_i3_7100.webp&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Fig 1. I used an Intel Core i3-7100 CPU for lower power consumption&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple way to clean a Lenovo ThinkPad Case</title>
      <link>/posts/simple_way_to_clean_a_lenovo_thinkpad_case/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 15:27:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/simple_way_to_clean_a_lenovo_thinkpad_case/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;past&#34;&gt;Past&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isopropyl is a great way to clean up a lot of plastic, but I found that while it’s helpful for removing grime, caked on stickers (Goo Gone), and other crud, it doesn’t always leave a nice finish. A few years back a volunteer at the Computer Recycling Project mentioned interning at a small computer store where they used Mr. Clean Magic Erasers to clean-up the top of ThinkPads. True to what he said, Mr. Clean Magic Erasers do seem to be a pretty good job on the top of ThinkPads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning our KODI media centre</title>
      <link>/posts/transitioning_our_kodi_media_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:49:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/transitioning_our_kodi_media_centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-more-to-a-low-power-solution&#34;&gt;Moving more to a low-power solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several months back I replaced the motherboard in the KODI media centre PC that sits in our living room. For many years our media centre has been rocking a Gigabyte motherboard with a second generation Core i7-2600 CPU. The Core i7-2600 came out in Q4 of 2010, making it almost 14 years old at the time I’m writing this. Still, it’s not a bad CPU. For several years it was the system I was compressing our movie collection on as the A8-5600K 4 core APU that was in my workstation (at the time) had about half the performance of the i7-2600. But about six months ago I replaced the CPU and motherboard with a still old, but more modern solution, a MSI motherboard and an Intel Core i3-7100.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux on the Lenovo Thinkstation C20 (MT-M 4265-93u)</title>
      <link>/posts/linux_on_the_lenovo_thinkstation_c20_mt_m_4265_93u/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:38:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/linux_on_the_lenovo_thinkstation_c20_mt_m_4265_93u/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is an older post, reposted from the old web site. The project has since mostly switched to Linux Mint XFCE
versions 21.3 (Virginia) and 22.1 (Xia). We still have Xubuntu 24.04.2 on our PXE server, but only install it on request.
Our checklist has evolved and we&amp;rsquo;ve separated some steps into other checklists.
See my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chaslinux&#34;&gt;github repositories&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;workstation-class-hardware-at-a-deeply-discounted-price&#34;&gt;Workstation class hardware at a deeply discounted price&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every now and then the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworkingcentre.org/cr/&#34;&gt;Computer Recycling Project&lt;/a&gt; at The Working Centre gets a really interesting piece of hardware donated. As a not-for-profit project, most of our equipment is aimed at people who are lower income. This generally translates into lower prices, even for some equipment others would list for a lot more. But that doesn’t mean the project just wipes the machines, installs Linux, and dumps the equipment on a sales shelf… often equipment requires a little, or a lot more work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xubuntu 24.04 bugs so far - May 3 2024</title>
      <link>/posts/xubuntu_2404_bugs_so_far_may_3_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:12:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/xubuntu_2404_bugs_so_far_may_3_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; While I tried using Linux Mint XFCE at home for awhile, I still found Xubuntu 24.04.2 works best for my use
cases. There are some filesystem differences, and while I was adverse to snaps because of control issues, I&amp;rsquo;m finding they
have some advantages over flatpak that I like. This is a repost from the old website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;xubuntu-linux-version-2404-is-out&#34;&gt;Xubuntu Linux version 24.04 is out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 24.04 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://xubuntu.org&#34;&gt;Xubuntu&lt;/a&gt; Linux is now out! Xubuntu Linux has been a staple of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworkingcentre.org/cr/&#34;&gt;Computer Recycling Project&lt;/a&gt; @ The Working Centre since 2010. With the project switching mostly to Linux, it’s now more important than ever that we’re up to date on trends, and new developments that affect the project. This new version of Xubuntu has a number of nice improvements, but in my testing on several different machines I’ve run into a number of issues as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell PowerEdge T110 II Network Attached Storage (NAS) build</title>
      <link>/posts/dell_poweredge_t110_ii_nas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 09:38:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dell_poweredge_t110_ii_nas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-the-kodi-entertainment-system&#34;&gt;Migrating the KODI entertainment system&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5th I mentioned that we’re Running out of space on our media center. In the comments of that post I followed up outlining a plan to buy another 8TB drive (for a total of 3 x 8TB drives) in order to do a RAID Z1 (for 16TB of space). But in order to do that I would need to reformat the drives, which means I also needed a plan to back up our media center data. I hinted at that solution in the comments too: 4 x 3TB drives in a RAID Z1 – which would give me 9TB of space (1 x 3TB is the spare), just enough to back up all the data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prince of Persia for Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/prince_of_persia_for_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 11:47:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/prince_of_persia_for_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;prince-of-persia---a-classic-game-for-dos&#34;&gt;Prince of Persia - a classic game for DOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first ran Prince of Persia on PC-DOS I remember thinking, “finally, a DOS game that rivals the fun I had on Commodore 64 games.” I was never very good at the game (and that continues today), but it’s a classic game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original DOS version has a port for Linux which you can find on github here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NagyD/SDLPoP?tab=readme-ov-file&#34;&gt;https://github.com/NagyD/SDLPoP?tab=readme-ov-file&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-simplest-method-to-install-sdlpop-on-ubuntuxubuntu-linux&#34;&gt;The simplest method to install SDLPoP on Ubuntu/Xubuntu Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re on Xubuntu, or another Ubuntu-variant, there is a snap for the game (called sdlpop). To install the snap simply open a terminal and type:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedroid - Paradroid (C64) for Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/freedroid_paradroid_for_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 11:20:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/freedroid_paradroid_for_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;paradroid-has-a-version-for-linux&#34;&gt;Paradroid, has a version for Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in the Commodore 64 era, I’m particularly fond of the games of that age. Games in that era tended to be simpler, but sometimes within that simplicity were some really neat concepts. Paradroid was one of those games that was particularly unique and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a really good look-back at Paradroid on the LemonTube64 Youtube channel here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/kkEBccMEhXs&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/kkEBccMEhXs&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedroid “classic” is a port of the game to Linux. The website for Freedroid classic might be a bit confusing when you first arrive because the same developers also worked on an isometric 3D-like game they called FreedroidRPG. The web site for both is:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reboot to the BIOS from Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/reboot_to_the_bios_from_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 15:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/reboot_to_the_bios_from_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-systemd-based-distributions-its-possible-to-boot-to-the-bios-from-linux&#34;&gt;On systemd-based distributions it’s possible to boot to the BIOS from Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself working on a computer that’s just so blindingly fast that you just cannot mash the key you need to get into the BIOS fast enough? It might be possible to reboot from your Linux system into the BIOS of your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all systems support this feature. On the one system we tested this on which didn’t boot to the BIOS the error message mentioned something about the EFI partition. But I was able to successfully run the command on a couple of systems, a 4th gen and 8th gen system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cannot click after laptop lid closed and re-opened - Xubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/cannot_click_after_laptop_lid_closed_and_reopened_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 12:14:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/cannot_click_after_laptop_lid_closed_and_reopened_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-problem-is-power-management-workaround&#34;&gt;The problem is power management (workaround)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve installed Xubuntu 22.04 on your laptop and things are going smoothly… Then you close the lid on your laptop and discover when you open it back up again that when you move the mouse it moves, but you cannot right or left click for some reason? The issue appears to be with power management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work around we found that appears to fix this is to edit the file:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding a laser printer as a shared network printer in Xubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/adding_a_laser_printer_as_a_shared_network_printer_in_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 16:09:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/adding_a_laser_printer_as_a_shared_network_printer_in_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;switching-printers-at-home&#34;&gt;Switching printers at home&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than running out of toner, there was nothing wrong with the HP Laserjet P1102w printer we have at home. The printer printed cleanly, was compact, and was connected to our wireless network, so any machine on our network could print to it. In fact, I was planning on buying more toner this evening after we did our usual scouring of thrift shops. I thought there was a small chance I might find the right HP 85A toner at one of the stores we planned to go to. I did find some other toner at one of the thrift shops, and the $5.95 price tag wasn’t bad, but it was for a different model in the same line of printers. But this was actually after spotting an even better deal, an HP Laserjet 1320 duplex printer for a whopping $10.95.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Fix] OBS Studio records static desktop image, no movement</title>
      <link>/posts/obs_studio_records_static_desktop_image_no_movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 16:18:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/obs_studio_records_static_desktop_image_no_movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;obs-is-awesome&#34;&gt;OBS is awesome!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Broadcasting Software, also known as OBS Studio, is an awesome piece of free and open source software that lets you capture audio and video from a wide variety of sources: screen capture, webcam, audio capture from the system, from an external source, from static images, slide shows, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been awhile since I’ve used OBS to capture the desktop of one of the systems at work, an ASUS M51AC desktop with an i7-4770 CPU, 16GB of RAM, and a 256GB SSD. I installed OBS 30.0.1 and started to record a video of the desktop, using the webcam microphone for audio. After a bit of tweaking, adjusting Xubuntu’s microphone sensitivity, I managed to get audio recording correctly so audio levels did not “clip” (go into the red) in OBS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating Discord on Xubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/updating_discord_on_xubuntu_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:28:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/updating_discord_on_xubuntu_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;great-and-a-pain&#34;&gt;Great, and a pain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord is one of those programs I love to hate. I like Discord because it’s a good way for people to connect with me about Computer Recycling, and I find it really handy for connecting with people about Game Development and Game Jams. But the process for updating Discord on Linux isn’t good. Normally, I update most software on my system by opening a terminal (Windows Key + T) and typing:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knights of Pen &amp; Paper II</title>
      <link>/posts/knights_of_pen_and_paper_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 12:25:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/knights_of_pen_and_paper_ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-dice-game-with-a-sense-of-humour&#34;&gt;A dice game with a sense of humour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If games like &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/200710/Torchlight_II/&#34;&gt;Torchlight II&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://diablo3.blizzard.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;Diablo III&lt;/a&gt;, or my favourite - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grimdawn.com/&#34;&gt;Grim Dawn&lt;/a&gt; are your thing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/310060/Knights_of_Pen_and_Paper_2/&#34;&gt;Knights of Pen &amp;amp; Paper II&lt;/a&gt; will seem like a snooze-fest to you. While Knights has elements of a role playing game, it’s not an “Action” role playing game (ARPG), but more mimics the kind of play you might get from playing Dungeons and Dragons with a game master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the game is NOT multiplayer, so one of the best parts of D&amp;amp;D is missing from Knights of Pen &amp;amp; Paper II, but if you’re okay with playing solo, this might be a fun title for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial GameMaker experience under Xubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/initial_gamemaker_experience_under_xubuntu_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 13:32:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/initial_gamemaker_experience_under_xubuntu_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;previous-gamemaker-experience&#34;&gt;Previous GameMaker experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought version 1.4 of the Gamemaker game engine on a Humble Bundle many years ago. At the time Gamemaker ONLY ran under Microsoft Windows. It was possible to export games to Linux (Ubuntu/Debian-specifically), but you couldn’t run the game engine itself under Linux. Version 2.x came along, and I paid to upgrade to 2.x as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time between when I bought 1.4 and 2.x I started working on my Asteroids-like clone, Fasteroids: (&lt;a href=&#34;https://chaslinux.itch.io/fasteroids)&#34;&gt;https://chaslinux.itch.io/fasteroids)&lt;/a&gt;. Many professional developers suggest starting and finishing a project as quickly as you can, then moving on to something else. Of course I didn’t listen and kept adding “features” to Fasteroids, which lead to the game being pretty messed up, and me losing interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First experience trying to learn Unity on Xubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/first_experience_trying_to_learn_unity_on_xubuntu_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 11:57:28 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/first_experience_trying_to_learn_unity_on_xubuntu_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this experience, and some back and forth with GameMaker, the GameMaker team switched the licensing back to a one time fee (except for console exports),
and they released a beta version of the engine for Ubuntu-based systems. The team continues to update this beta along with the normal code. Since I previously
had experience with GameMaker I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to stick with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been really thrilled with it as bugs I&amp;rsquo;ve run into have been fixed a short while after
I&amp;rsquo;ve reported them, and the community have been great helping me solve issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fasteroids - An Asteroids-like game for Linux and Windows</title>
      <link>/posts/fasteroids_an_asteroids_like_game_for_linux_and_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 18:54:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fasteroids_an_asteroids_like_game_for_linux_and_windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;reviving-an-old-project&#34;&gt;Reviving an old project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I realized that, since redoing this web site, I still haven’t added any information about the game I made back in 2017-2020. Recently I revived Fasteroids, and made some changes to both simplify the game, but also with the idea that the game should be able to scale to 4k in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I ramble on more, you can download Fasteroids for Linux or Windows from:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Fix] Vikings - Wolves of Midgard crashing after kalypso startup screen</title>
      <link>/posts/fix_vikings_wolves_of_midgard_crashing_after_kalypso_startup_screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 20:25:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/fix_vikings_wolves_of_midgard_crashing_after_kalypso_startup_screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;vikings--wolves-of-midgard-crashes-after-the-kalypso-video&#34;&gt;Vikings – Wolves of Midgard (crashes after the Kalypso video)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vikings – Wolves of Midgard is a linear action role playing game (ARPG) that lets you go back and repeat quests several times until you’re overpowered. Recently I’ve tried a number of role playing games only to find they were lacking in graphics, the controls were too jank, or they just required obscene amounts of time to make any progress. I like Vikings – Wolves of Midgard, because I find that despite the fact that the story is almost aways the same, you can complete quests over and over again until you’re overpowered. The controls are not bad, especially compared to some of the games I’ve played lately. Best of all it runs natively under Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legend of Grimrock - a better Bards Tale III</title>
      <link>/posts/legend_of_grimrock_a_better_bards_tale_iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 20:38:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/legend_of_grimrock_a_better_bards_tale_iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;bards-tale-iii--my-introduction-to-3d-like-adventure&#34;&gt;Bards Tale III – my introduction to 3D like adventure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 1980’s I worked for Simcoe Computer Consultants at the 400 Market, outside of Barrie, Ontario. The 400 Market was a mixed market of many vendors, one of which was Simcoe Computer Consultants. I spent the weekends manning the company’s booth, selling the odd item, and spreading the word about the company’s computers and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One weekend Cec, one of the company owners, mentioned that a lead from the market had helped them sell a bunch of computers, and I was welcome to pick a piece of software as a reward. I picked Bard’s Tale III, Thief of Fate, a dungeon crawling game with a 3D-like interface. Bard’s Tale III quickly became one of my favourite games, it mixed D&amp;amp;D elements with a more urgent element where one wrong turn could lead to a face to face encounter with deadly monsters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Torchlight II for SteamOS and Linux</title>
      <link>/posts/torchlight_ii_for_steamos_and_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 19:55:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/torchlight_ii_for_steamos_and_linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;almost-11-years-old-and-still-fun&#34;&gt;Almost 11 years old, and still fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/200710/Torchlight_II/&#34;&gt;Torchlight II&lt;/a&gt; (opens to Steam page) was released in September of 2012, several months after the release of Diablo III. Max Schaefer and Matt Uelmen, both developers who worked on Diablo and Diablo II, helped form Runic Games, the company behind Torchlight II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both Torchlight II and Diablo II are considered ARPGs (Action Role Playing Games), Torchlight II feels like it has less linear gameplay. Both games drive you to destroy an end boss, and both have side quests, but Torchlight II is purposefully moddable, and a lot less dark. In Diablo and Diablo II you fight demons, devils, undead, and other demonic monstrosities. In Torchlight II you find yourself pitted against more Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons variety monsters, Mind Flayers, Werewolves, Bandits, Manticores, and a more mixed variety of monsters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Linux BASH shell script to create a PDF of monitor information - findmonitor.sh</title>
      <link>/posts/a_linux_shell_script_to_create_a_pdf_of_monitor_information_findmonitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 13:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/a_linux_shell_script_to_create_a_pdf_of_monitor_information_findmonitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-findmonitorsh&#34;&gt;About findmonitor.sh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Note: This script is NOT compatible with systems running Wayland. We use Xubuntu Linux at our project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Working Centre’s not-for-profit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworkingcentre.org/cr/&#34;&gt;Computer Recycling Project&lt;/a&gt; sometimes receives donations of many monitors all at once. Our previous method for handling monitors was to set them up, run them through a bunch of tests, print a label on our label printer, and enter the monitor into our point of sale. This method hasn’t worked very well for us when we’ve received a lot of monitors all at once. Large amounts of monitors were sitting untested for awhile because we didn’t have the resources to do the old process for each monitor. We needed a faster way to figure out some of the details of monitors, and make them easier to sell without needing to create labels and enter everything into the point of sale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handbrake performance on more than 6 cores</title>
      <link>/posts/handbrake_performance_on_more_than_6_cores/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 19:45:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/handbrake_performance_on_more_than_6_cores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;diminishing-returns-after-6-cores-but-not-for-all-media&#34;&gt;Diminishing returns after 6 cores, but not for all media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handbrake is a video transcoder. It’s normally used to convert and compress video from a format into a more compressed format. Handbrake comes in a command line version, handbrake-cli, and a graphical version, handbrake. I’ve seen it mentioned several times that Handbrake is best at 6 cores or less, after that the encoding returns are diminishing. I thought this was the case with some of my experimentation, but it seems the answer is more complicated – it depends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardware detection script for Linux refurbishers</title>
      <link>/posts/hardware_detection_script_for_linux_refurbishers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 14:29:08 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/hardware_detection_script_for_linux_refurbishers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-the-script&#34;&gt;About the script&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote the hardware.sh BASH script to make it a bit simpler for volunteers at The Working Centre’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theworkingcentre.org/cr/&#34;&gt;Computer Recycling Project&lt;/a&gt; to figure out what hardware was in a computer. For more than a dozen years we’ve been asking volunteers to gather information from the BIOS, or using phoronix-test-suite under our PXE booted Debian Live environment. Volunteers would write the information on quarter page-sized sheets we would attach to each computer. While this was a useful function to help volunteers get to know hardware in a computer, there were a few problems with this method:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 22.04 Jammy Jellyfish</title>
      <link>/posts/ubuntu_2204_jammy_jellyfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 18:57:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ubuntu_2204_jammy_jellyfish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-computer-recycling-project-used-ubuntu-linux-from-2006-to-2010&#34;&gt;The Computer Recycling Project used Ubuntu Linux from 2006 to 2010&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a challenge to talk about Xubuntu Linux without referring to Xubuntu’s more popular relative, Ubuntu Linux. Ubuntu Linux was started in 2004 and based around a then popular flavour/distribution of Linux, Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debian Linux was the distribution The Working Centre’s Computer Recycling Project initially used to develop our own Linux distribution, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wclp.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;WCLP – Working Centre Linux Project&lt;/a&gt;, way back in 2001. By 2006 the project had switched to Ubuntu Linux. Ubuntu Linux was a rising star back in 2006, it made installing “difficult to install” proprietary drivers easy (compared to Debian). And because Ubuntu was based on Debian, people with Debian experience could easily adapt to Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
